thecountrycook.net 2019-04-23

# Privacy Policy | The Country Cook

The Country Cook (www.thecountrycook.net) (“Website”) is governed by the following Privacy Policy. 

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website. 

 **WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW IS IT USED?**

  *  **Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website:** We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form. In addition, we may ask you to create a user profile, which would allow you to create a username and password. We will store the username, but your password will not be visible in our records. 

  *  **Information We Collect from Others:** We may receive information about you from other sources. For example, if you use a third-party software through the site, they may transfer information to us for fulfillment. 

  *  **Automatically-Collected Information:** We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked. 

  *  **Cookies:** We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

 **HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED**

We may use the information collected in the following ways: 

  * To operate and maintain the Website; 
  * To create your account, identify you as a user of the Website, and customize the Website for your account; 
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings; 
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts; 
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries; 
  * To provide you with user support; 
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website; 
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

 **THIRD-PARTY USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies. The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers: 

  * [Google Analytics](https://policies.google.com/privacy) – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics. 
  * [Mailchimp](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications. 
  * [Rafflecopter](https://www.rafflecopter.com/privacy-policy) – this service is used for giveaways on the site. Your name, email address and IP address are captured at time of entry.
  * [InLinkz](https://www.inlinkz.com/new/privacy.php) – This service is used to allow content creators to share links to their websites in a weekly post we call Weekend Potluck. This Information collected includes email address, internet protocol (IP) addresses as well as browser type, URLs of referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, locale and language preferences

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion. 

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

 **ANONYMOUS DATA**

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies. 

 **PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION**

If you create a user profile on the Website or leave a comment, certain information may be publicly visible. 

 **COOKIES**

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein. 

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

#### ADVERTISING

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [https://optout.networkadvertising.org](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing. If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at [info@adthrive.com](mailto:info@adthrive.com). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

 **SPONSORED CONTENT TRACKING PIXELS  
**This Website may engage in sponsored campaigns with various influencer networks, brands, and agencies. All sponsored content is duly disclosed in accordance with the FTC’s requirements. From time to time, these sponsored campaigns utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons), which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience. This information is collected by the sponsoring company to track the results of the campaign. No personally identifiable information collected by the Website is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.

 **AFFILIATE PROGRAM MARKETING  
**The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.  

The Country Cook is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

 **NEWSLETTERS**  
On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

 **PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**

We may collect personally identifiable information from users in a variety of ways in connection with activities, services, features, or resources we make available on this site including, but not limited to, email newsletters, contests/giveaways, and the Just A Pinch Food Group Recipe Box. Where applicable, users may be asked for a name, email address, and other personally identifiable information. This is collected from users only if they submit such information voluntarily. Certain features and services, like the Just A Pinch Food Group Recipe Box, may offer the user the ability to opt-in to services provided by third-party websites. It is the user’s responsibility to review the policies of any third-party websites before opting-in to their services. This privacy policy does not cover the use of information collected by these third-party websites. Users can always refuse to supply personally identifiable information with the knowledge that it may prevent them from engaging in certain site activities or features.

 **RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

 **Opt-out** – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at brandie@thecountrycook.net to be removed from our mailing list. 

 **SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you 

 **FOR RESIDENTS OF THE EUROPEAN UNION**

 **Access** – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to brandie@thecountrycook.net. 

 **Amend** – You may contact us at brandie@thecountrycook.netto amend or update your personal information. 

 **Forget** – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to brandie@thecountrycook.net. 

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

 **CHILDREN’S INFORMATION**

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at brandie@thecountrycook.netand we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

 **CONTACT INFORMATION**

At any time, please contact us at brandie@thecountrycook.net for questions related to this Privacy Policy. 

Last updated: July 25, 2018

 **ONESIGNAL PUSH NOTIFICATION PRIVACY POLICY DISCLOSURES:**

OneSignal., a U.S. company located at 411 Borel Ave Suite 512, San Mateo, CA 94402 (“OneSignal” “we,” “us,” and “our”), provides this privacy policy because we believe that consumers should have clear and comprehensive ways to understand how information about them is collected and used – both to provide our services and for third party advertising purposes. We’ve tried to write this policy in a way that is easy for consumers to understand at a “high level,” while still providing detail to allow sophisticated users (and privacy advocates) to understand what data models we’re engaged in, and more generally, how interest-based advertising works.

We’ve also provided a section about the choices that you have with respect to “interest based advertising,”, and we encourage you to read that section and exercise your “opt out” rights if you’re inclined to do that. (But because interest based advertising leads to more relevant (and thus, less annoying) advertising, we hope you won’t do that.)

### Introduction and Background

OneSignal’s provides SDKs to mobile app developers and websites, and data and analytics services to other data partners and advertisers. These web and mobile SDKs permit app developers and websites to send, manage, optimize and customize push notifications to their users. All of these services (further described in this privacy policy) are referred to collectively as our “ **Services** ,” and all of these developers, website operators, partners and advertisers are referred to collectively as our “ **Clients**.”

This privacy policy (the “ **Privacy Policy** ”) explains how we may collect, use, store, and disclose information about the end users (“ **End Users** ”) of third-party mobile applications and websites that use our Services. We also collect information on our corporate website(s), including any website on which this Privacy Policy is posted. We separately describe how we collect, use and share that website information (“ **OneSignal Website Information** ”) in [Section 4](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy#4-how-we-use-and-share-information-collected-on-the-oneSignal-website), below.

We encourage consumers to learn about how information (including information we collect) can be used to market to them, and how to exercise their choices to permit or, if they prefer, to limit such marketing. We describe some ways consumers can exercise that choice or opt out of marketing in [Section 6](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy#6-consumer-control-amp-opt-out-options), below, titled **Consumer Control & Opt Out Options **.

 **1\. Our SDKs: Information We Collect and Services We Provide**

We refer to the information we collect from our SDKs as the ‘ **SDK Information**.” The SDK Information includes (or may include) the following:

 **Information Collected About End Users by Our Web SDKs**

  * Web pages visited that have implemented the SDK , and information about those visits (e.g., session duration, time-stamp, referring URLs)
  * What push notifications an End User has been sent
  * Information about End User’s transactions and interactions with apps and websites
  * IP address, from which geographic location may be inferred, as well as system configuration information
  * Email address which we may (in our discretion) hash or otherwise deidentify
  * Information about an End User’s browser, such as, browser language type and version of operating system (e.g., Android, iOS); network provider; language setting; time zone
  * A unique cookie identifier, which may uniquely identify an End User (such as in de-identified or anonymous form). These cookies may be associated with other Information, including with Data Segments, which we describe in [Section 3](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy#3-how-and-why-we-share-the-sdk-information).

 **Information Collected About End Users by Our Mobile SDKs**

  * When permitted by the operating system, OneSignal may check to see if the device has specific applications installed, based on a limited list, for purposes that include attribution, relevancy of ads, and relevancy of notifications related to those applications.
  * Purchases made within an app.
  * Information about End User’s transactions and interactions with apps and websites
  * Mobile advertising identifiers, such as iOS IDFAs and Android Advertising IDs (“Mobile IDs”). These Mobile IDs may be associated with other Information, including with Data Segments.
  * Precise Location information, generally an End User’s lat/long data (i.e., GPS-level data) or WiFi information, which we may associate with Mobile IDs, and which may be collected whether or not an app is in use.
  * Email address, which we may (in our discretion) hash or otherwise deidentify.
  * IP address as well as system configuration information
  * Information associated with or related to devices, such as device type (e.g., mobile, tablet); type and version of operating system (e.g., Android, iOS); network provider; mobile browser (e.g. Safari, Chrome, etc.); language setting; time zone; and network status type (such as WiFi).

As noted above, we refer to all of the above collectively as the “ **SDK Information**.”

 **2\. How We Use the SDK Information**

We use the SDK Information to provide a variety of Services to our Clients. This includes:

  * To Provide Our App and Website Services. We use the SDK Information to offer and support app and website features provided through the SDKs, including those related to push notifications. This includes, for instance, providing customer, technical and operational support for these features, detecting and protecting against errors, fraud, or other criminal activity; resolving disputes and enforcing our EULA and other rights we may have. It also includes analyzing, customizing, and improving the features we offer Clients.
  * To provide information and analytics to our Clients about the use of these app and website features provided through the SDKs, or to help app developers and website operators create or enhance user profiles.
  * To create inferences about End Users categorized into “Data Segments” or to help Clients do so. For instance, if SDK Information indicates that a particular device is frequently seen at restaurants, we might categorize a user for targeting of local restaurant offers. Or, if a user is frequently seen at sports stadiums, we might categorize the user as a “Sports Fan.”
  * To develop and use “predictive models” – data models that try to predict End Users’ potential future behavior and interests on a per-device basis or across devices
  * To analyze ad performance, for instance, by attributing End Users’ app installations, web visits, or store visits to ad campaigns.
  * Sometimes, the SDK Information may be used (by us or ad and data platforms we work with) to resolve identities across multiple devices, such as to match IP addresses or hashed emails to link an End User across (for instance) browsers, mobile devices, tablets, set top boxes, or other devices.
  * Sometimes the SDK Information may be combined (by us or ad and data platforms we work with), to perform any of the above functions, or other advertising, marketing or analytics services. Or, we may aggregate and create data “models” to do this – creating algorithms in order to predict certain trends and things that different End Users might have in common, for instance.
  * We may provide End Users’ email addresses (which we generally “hash” or render non-human readable) to online data platforms that “match” this information to online cookies or Mobile IDs in their system, and tie the information (or associated IDs) to further interest-based or demographic data about End Users. This may be done, for instance, to target advertising or provide analytics to brands and other companies.

We, or ad and data platforms we work with, may deploy online cookies to track users across websites, or to associate users (and these cookies) with Mobile IDs. We or they may do this to resolve user identifies across platforms, and to better or more accurately target relevant ads to users (such as to a brand’s customers). You can learn more about cookies and similar technologies, such as web beacons and SDKs, in the Section titled “ **Cookies, Pixel Tags and SDKs**.” We may also “append” or combine certain SDK Information (such as hashed email addresses) to other information provided by third party data providers, to learn more about End Users or to provide advertising and analytics services.

 **3\. How and Why We Share the SDK Information.**

To Provide Services to Websites and Apps Using the SDKs

  * We share the SDK Information with service providers, contractors and other companies to fulfill your orders, operate our business, communicate with you and make available our Services and this Website. These service providers may help us perform any of the activities set forth in [Section 2](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy#2). For instance, we may share certain of the information we collect or receive with companies that help us with billing and payment, marketing, advertising and email marketing,
  * data enhancement (e.g., to provide more relevant offers), website hosting, technology and customer support, web and marketing analytics, anti-fraud or security operations, and other operational, marketing or business support.
  * We likewise may share the SDK Information or Data Segments we create with website operators and app developers (for instance, related to push notifications they send) for their advertising, analytics, or other purposes.

To Provide Services to Marketers, Advertisers and Platforms They Work With

We also share SDK Information to provide or help us to provide advertising and marketing services as we have described in [Section 3](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy#3-how-and-why-we-share-the-sdk-information), including as follows:

  * With advertisers and their marketing providers, so they may provide targeted content and advertising to you on websites and mobile applications With other third parties that target advertising. For those familiar with the online ad ecosystem, these may include demand-side and supply-side advertising platforms, data management platforms, advertising agency trading desks, proximity solution providers, and other advertising technology providers, so they may provide targeted content and advertising to End Users and others on third-party websites, mobile applications, and other advertising mediums (email, direct mail, display media), and so that they may measure the effectiveness of this marketing.
  * Similarly, we may work with service providers who, to enhance consumer privacy, use a non-human readable “hashed” version of Information such as an email address when sending advertising offers by email or display advertising (which may be linked to a cookie as described above).
  * Sometimes we provide information (such as IP address, but excluding precise lat/long coordinates) to third party platforms to help advertisers identify common users across different devices or browsers – for instance, to identify a common set of users on both mobile devices and tablets, as well as the web.

The processes we’ve described above often involves cookies or similar technologies, which may be associated with other information about you, e.g., your interests, demographics or transactions. This is known generally as “Interest-Based Advertising.” We encourage users who are interested in controlling or learning about this type of “interest-based advertising” to go to [Section 6](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy#6-consumer-control-amp-opt-out-options), titled “ **Consumer Control & Opt-Out Options **, or go to this this page operated by the online ad industry trade association.

We may also share the SDK Information with third parties:

  * If an End User or Client requests or authorizes
  * If the information is provided to: (1) comply in good faith with applicable laws, rules, regulations, governmental and quasi-governmental requests, court orders, or subpoenas; (2) enforce our Terms of Use or other agreements; or (3) protect our rights, property, or safety or the rights, property, or safety of our users or any other person or entity
  * If the disclosure is done as part of, including as part of due diligence for, a purchase, transfer, or sale of services or assets (e.g., in the event that substantially all of our assets are acquired by another party, any information we have may be one of the transferred assets) or in the event of bankruptcy

Even when you no longer access the SDKs, we may continue to use and share your Information as described in this Privacy Policy.

 **4\. How we Use and Share Information Collected on the OneSignal Website(s)**

 **Website Information We Collect**

We collect the following information from visitors to our websites (the “OneSignal Website Information”, including the website on which this Privacy Policy appears (“OneSignal Website(s)”):

  * Volunteered: You may share information with us on the OneSignal Websites when you request information from us, fill out a form on our website, or interact with us in other ways. This information may include personal information, such as your name, email address, and other contact information.
  * Passively Collected (e.g., Cookies and Unique IDs): We use automated mechanisms, such as cookies, pixels, and other locally stored objects (such as “IndexedDB)”) that we associate with unique identifiers in order to keep track of visitor interactions with the OneSignal Websites. (You can learn more about these technologies below in the Section titled “Cookies, Pixel Tags and SDKs”)). We may use third party-services such as Google Analytics, in which case those third parties gather information such as your IP address, browser type, the webpage from which you came to our website, and the times of your access to the OneSignal Website. In addition, as you browse our website, advertising cookies may be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. Our display advertising partners may then help us retarget ads to you on other sites based on your interactions with the OneSignal Website. To “opt out” of having your information used to tailor ads to you in this way by third party ad platforms that we may work with or provide data to, please review the Section below titled “Consumer Control and Opt Out Options” to learn how to opt-out of these services and instead receive generic, non-tailored ads.

 **How We Use the OneSignal Website Information**

In addition to the uses described above, we use the OneSignal Website Information (alone or in combination) to provide, market, and operate the OneSignal Websites and Services. Among other things, by collecting the OneSignal Website Information, we are able to

  * Maintain and offer access to the OneSignal Websites and Services and optimize how they’re offered to our Clients.
  * Send information about our products and services, including marketing communications.
  * Respond to your questions, concerns, or customer service inquiries.
  * Customize the content and advertising you see on the OneSignal Websites, across the Internet, and elsewhere.

 **How We Share the OneSignal Website Information**

We may share the OneSignal Website Information as follows:

  * As part of a business sale, merger, consolidation, investment, change in control, transfer of substantial assets, reorganization or liquidation, or in connection with steps taken in anticipation of such an event (e.g., due diligence).
  * With our corporate affiliates.
  * With third parties that help us to provide the OneSignal Websites or Services, such as entities that help us make the OneSignal Websites or Services available and functional (such as hosting services); entities that help us make available or transmit any information we hold (such as helping us send emails, process payments, and manage customer information); and entities that help us (including our contractors, agents, and affiliates) provide technical, customer, billing, administrative, event planning, marketing or operational services to us or our Clients.
  * When required by law or in response to lawful process, such as a subpoena, or to cooperate in good faith with a request from a government or law enforcement agency or official.
  * If we believe sharing the information may prevent physical, financial or other harm, injury or loss; or we believe is necessary to protect our, or any other person’s or entity’s, interests; or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual unlawful activity.
  * We also may disclose your information under circumstances not mentioned here with your prior consent.

 **5\. Cookies, Pixel Tags and SDKs**

  *  **Cookies and Pixel Tags.**  
Cookies are small data files containing a string of characters, such as an anonymous unique browser identifier. Cookies are stored on your computer or other device and act as unique tags that identify your device or browser. Our servers may send your device a cookie when you visit the OneSignal Websites, and our Clients and Partners may do likewise on our Websites, our Clients’ websites, and elsewhere. A pixel tag (also commonly known as a web beacon or clear GIF) is an invisible 1 x 1 pixel that is placed on certain web pages. When you access web pages on which a pixel tag is deployed, the pixel tag may generate a generic notice of the visit and permit OneSignal, our Clients or Partners to set or read cookies. Pixel tags are used in combination with cookies to anonymously track the activity on a website by a particular browser on a particular device. If you disable cookies, pixel tags simply detect an anonymous website visit. OneSignal, alone or with our Clients and Partners, may use cookies to, among other things, “remember” you (e.g., when you visit the OneSignal Websites or the websites of our Clients or Partners), track trends, and collect information about how you use our Clients’ or Partners’ websites or interact with advertising. We and partners we work with use cookies to provide relevant content to you and replace non-relevant ads with ads that better match your interests. We may sometimes use other locally stored objects in ways similar to how we use cookies. Often, these objects are deleted when you clear your browser cookie cache, but because this may not always occur (depending on the browser you use), we recommend that if you wish to opt out of notification features or third party interestbased advertising you instead follow the steps we have set forth in [Section 6](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy#6-consumer-control-amp-opt-out-options) titled “Consumer Control & Opt-Out Options.”
  *  **Mobile Device Identifiers and SDKs.**  
We may use or work with partners who use mobile SDKs (including our own SDKs, which are described in more detail in this Policy) to collect information, such as mobile identifiers (e.g., IDFAs and Android Advertising IDs), and information related to how mobile devices and their users interact with our Services and those using our Services. The SDK is computer code that app developers can include in their apps to enable ads to be shown, data to be collected, and related services to be implemented. We may use this technology, for instance, to analyze or measure certain advertising through mobile applications and browsers based on information associated with your mobile device. If you would like to opt-out from having ads tailored to you in this way on your mobile device, please follow the instructions in the below Section titled “ **Consumer Control and Opt-Out Options**.”

As described in [Section 4](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy#4-how-we-use-and-share-information-collected-on-the-oneSignal-website) our Clients or Partners may use the above technologies (sometimes, in combination with each other or other data such as IP addresses or hashed or de-identified data files) to coordinate identifiers across platforms, browsers or devices, to more efficiently analyze or target advertising.

 **6\. Consumer Control & Opt-Out Options. **

In most cases, consumers have control over whether or not they would like to receive relevant advertisements and marketing email from our Clients.

  *  **Opting Out of OneSignal Push Notifications** You may in most cases opt out of receiving push notifications by going to your device “Settings” and clicking on “Notifications,” and then changing those settings for some or all of the apps on your device. (Different device configurations, or updates to devices, may affect or change how these settings work.)
  * Please[ click this link](https://documentation.onesignal.com/docs/unsubscribe-from-notifications) for more information about opting out.
  * Your choice to opt out of “Notifications” from the OneSignal platform will not affect ads placed by any other organization.
  *  **Opting Out of Online Interest-Based Advertising** You can opt out of many of the platforms and service providers that facilitate online interest-based advertising by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s consumer education and opt-out page, at <http://www.aboutads.info/>. This type of opt out is cookie based, which means that if you replace or upgrade your browser, or delete your cookies, you will need to opt out again. Opting out in this way will not prevent you from receiving ads – it will just make the ads you see less customized to you.
  *  **Opting Out of “Cross-App” Advertising on Mobile Devices** You can opt out of having your mobile advertising identifiers used for certain types of interest-based (also called “cross-app”) mobile behavioral advertising, by accessing the “settings” on your Apple or Android mobile device, as follows:
    * Apple Devices: If you have an Apple device, you can opt out of most app-based tracking for interest-based advertising by setting Limit Ad Tracking to ‘ON.’ You can do this by clicking on Settings -> Privacy -> Advertising and toggling Limit Ad Tracking to ‘ON.’
    * Android Devices: If you have an Android device, you can opt out of most app-based tracking for interest-based advertising by opening the Google Settings app on your device, selecting Ads, and then selecting the option to opt-out of interest-based ads.

Please note that these platforms control how these settings work, so the above may change. Likewise, if your device uses other platforms not described above, you should check the settings for those devices.

  *  **Additional Choices** Advertisers may also provide ways for you to opt out from or limit their collection of information from and about you. Please refer to the privacy policies for retailers, applications and websites to learn more about their privacy practices.You may opt not to receive promotional emails from us by contacting us as indicated below or by following the “unsubscribe” instructions in any promotional email you receive from us. Please note, however, that we may still send you non-promotional emails about your relationship with us.

7\. **Data Access and Retention**

Generally speaking, we retain the SDK Information and Website Information for as long as necessary to achieve our objectives as detailed in this Privacy Policy, and to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

8\. **Data Security**

We have administrative, technical, and physical safeguards in place in our physical facilities and in our computer systems, databases, and communications networks that are designed to protect information contained within our systems from loss, misuse, or alteration. No method of electronic transmission or storage is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee absolute security of your Personal Information and Non-Personal Information.

9\. **Third Party Websites and Apps**

We are not responsible for the privacy practices or disclosures of websites and applications that use our Services. Likewise, when you access the OneSignal Website, you may be directed to other websites that are also beyond our control. We encourage you to read the applicable privacy policies and terms and conditions of such third parties and websites, and the industry tools that we have referenced in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy, however, only applies to the OneSignal Site and the Services.

10\. **Users From Outside the United States**

The Website and our Services are provided, supported and hosted in the United States, and our operation of them is governed by United States law. If you are using the Site from outside the United States, be aware that your Information may be transferred to, stored and processed in the United States and other countries where our facilities are located. The data protection and other laws of the United States might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. By using the Site you consent to your information being transferred to our facilities and to the facilities of those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Policy.

11\. **Contacting Us**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@OneSignal.com](mailto:privacy@OneSignal.com).

12\. **Changes to This Privacy Policy**

If we make material changes to our privacy policy that may impact you, we will prominently post notice of the change on our website for a period of at least 30 days prior to the change becoming effective. We recommend that you check the Privacy Policy frequently so that you are informed of any changes.

13\. **Paid Plan Privacy Policy**

We also offer enterprise plans for customers interested in data privacy, priority support, or special terms which are not usually applicable to most clients. Enterprise Plans are subject to our [Paid Plan Privacy Policy.](https://onesignal.com/OneSignalSAASPrivacyPolicy.pdf)
